Guide to the Rainbow Families Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Rainbow Families records
1983-2011
MS 2006
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(6 boxes)
The collection consists of the records of Rainbow Families, a membership advocacy organization for gay and lesbian parents and their families. The records document the organization's efforts to provide support, organization, advocacy, and public education on behalf of gay and lesbian parents and their families, and consist of Board of Directors records, event records, membership records, strategic plans, and quarterly newsletters.
Rainbow Families
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of the records of Rainbow Families, a membership advocacy organization for gay and lesbian parents and their families. The records document the organization's efforts to provide support, organization, advocacy, and public education on behalf of gay and lesbian parents and their families, and consist of Board of Directors records, event records, membership records, strategic plans, and quarterly newsletters.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Rainbow Families was a membership organization founded in 1997 in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Its mission was to provide support, organization, advocacy, and public education on behalf of gay and lesbian parents and their families. Rainbow Families organized and sponsored conferences and and community-building events, published a quarterly newsletter, and provided its members with resources and referrals around issues such as adoption, legal and legislative policy, and school advocacy. In 2007, Rainbow Families merged with Familty Equality Council, becoming that organization's Midwest office.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged according to document type.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Family Equality Council, 2014.
Related Materials
Related material: Family Equality Council Records (MS 2000).
Adoptive parents; Families -- United States; Gay fathers; Gay men -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States; Gay parents; Gay rights -- United States; Lesbian mothers; LGBTQ resource; Family Equality Council; Rainbow Families
- Board of Directors records
  - By-laws, 2005 February 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Meeting agendas and minutes
    - 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 2-7)
    - 2002-2006 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
    - 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - Orientation and training materials, 1983-2006 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Philanthropic goals, 2003-2006 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Press, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Recruitment, 2000-2007 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Staff and board of directors retreats, 1998-2004 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Annual conference, 2008-2011 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
- Member and donor database, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
- Rainbow Families quarterly newsletter
  - 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 2000-2007 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
- Songs from the Heart Twin Cities Gay Men's Chorus, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Strategic plan, 2002-2006 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)